張凱鵬 (ZHANG, Kaipeng)

General Information

Currently I am a Final Year undergraduate student in Donghua University, Shanghai, and a visiting student in Multimedia Laboratory, Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology, Chinese Academy of Science. My research interests include computer vision and machine learning, particularly face analysis and deep learning.

Tel: (86) 18817957729 E-mail: kp_zhang@foxmail.com

Education

Undergraduate: in Computer Network Engineering (The class of excellent engineer), 2013-2016

Computer Science and Technology School (Expected)

Donghua University, Shanghai, China

GPA: Top 20%

Undergraduate: in Electronic Information Engineering,

2012-2013

College of Information, Mechanical and Electronic Engineering

Shanghai Normal University, Shanghai, China

GPA: Top 10%

Main Courses & Grades

Computer Image Processing (95) Discrete Mathematics (95) Computer Organization and Architecture (90)

TCP/IP Protocol (90) Data Structure (90) Principles of Operating System (96)

Research Interests

Computer Vision: Face analysis, face detection Recognition and Machine Learning: Deep learning

Publications

Kaipeng Zhang, Zhanpeng Zhang, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao, "Joint Face Detection and Alignment using Multi-task Cascaded Convolutional Networks," *IEEE Signal Processing Letters* (submitted)

Kaipeng Zhang, Lianzhi Tan, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao, "Gender and Smile Classification using Deep Convolutional Neural Networks," in *IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Workshops (CVPRW)*, 2016 (accepted)

One European Conference on Computer Vision 2016 (ECCV 2016) paper has been submitted.

Honors & Awards

ChaLearn Looking at People Challenge: Accessories Classification (CVPRW 2016)				First Price	2016
ChaLearn Looking at People Challenge: Smile and Gender Classification (CVPRW 2016)				First Price	2016
Outstanding Undergraduate Thesis		Donghua University			2016
China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling		Second Prize	Shanghai		2015
Mathematical Contest in Modeling	Second Prize	Donghua University			2015
Wuyi Mathematical Contest	Third Prize	Jiangsu Province			2015
MathorCup & CAA Worldwide Mathematical Contest		Winner Price	China		2015
China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling		Third Prize	Shanghai		2014
Mathematical Contest in Modeling	Third Prize	Donghua University			2014
ACM-ICPC Contest on Campus	Third Prize	Donghua University			2014
Second Prize Scholarship		Shanghai Norn	nal Universi	ty	2013
Mathematical Contest in Modeling	Second Prize	Shanghai Normal University		2012	

Internship

Shenzhen institutes of advanced technology, Chinese academy of sciences, visiting student

2015.07 - now

Research Experience

Gender and Smile Classification using Deep Convolutional Neural Networks

2016.03

leverage the multi-task learning and the general-to-specific fine-tuning scheme to enhance the performance of

1

Face detection and alignment by deep learning

- Joint face and facial landmark detection using cascaded CNNs framework.
- Achieve the state-of-the-art performance in FDDB, WIDER FACE benchmark for face detection and AFLW benchmark for face alignment in high running speed.

Project Experience

Useless commodity comment classification

2015.05

- Build comment vector model (Use jieba Chinese word segmentation module, TF-IDF formula, stacked autoencoder)
- Useless comment classification (Use random forest and K-means for labeled and none labeled data situation)

Microblog user modeling and public opinion analysis

2014.12 - now

- Build a user model based on ontology (Use TF-IDF formula, Baidu baike as ontology)
- Topic and public opinion analysis (Use LDA topic model and Random forest for public opinion classification)

The application of face recognition in video retrieval

2014.09 - 2014.11

- Use Eigenface for face recognition and retrieve video by personal identity
- The system runs on Hadoop for large-scale data processing

English & Professional Skill

English: CET4 (529)

Senior Network Engineer (approved and authorized by the Ministry of Human Resources an Social Security, China)

EMC Academic Associate, Information Storage and Management

EMC Academic Associate, Cloud Infrastructure and Services

C/C++, Python, and Matlab programming